[wind blowing]
[wind howling]
[phone ringing in distance]
[theme song playing]
♪ Take a little walk to the edge of town ♪
♪ Go across the tracks ♪
♪ Where the viaduct looms
Like a bird of doom ♪
♪ As it shifts and cracks ♪
♪ Where secrets lie in the border fires
In the humming wires ♪
[phone continues ringing]
♪ Hey, man, you know
You're never coming back ♪
Arthur.
[Arthur] "We cannot give you the assurance
you are asking for.
We expect payment in full."
Here's my favourite part.
"We have never even heard of your people,
so we are not afraid of your threats."
And they've signed it,
"The Angels of Retribution."
Hmm.
♪ He'll rekindle all the dreams ♪
♪ It took you a lifetime to destroy ♪
♪ He'll reach deep into the hole ♪
♪ Heal your shrinking soul ♪
♪ But there won't be a single thing
That you can do ♪
♪ He's a God, he's a man
He's a ghost, he's a guru ♪
[coins clatter]
♪ They're whispering his name
Through this disappearing land... ♪
They say they haven't even heard of us.
So tell Aberama and Isiah
to introduce themselves.
And Finn, you stay out of it.
♪ You don't have no money? ♪
♪ He'll get you some ♪
♪ You don't have no car? ♪
♪ He'll get you one ♪
♪ You don't have no self-respect
You feel like an insect ♪
♪ Well, don't you worry, buddy
'Cause here he comes ♪
♪ Through the ghettos and the barrio
And the Bowery and the slum ♪
♪ A shadow is cast wherever he stands ♪
♪ Stacks of green paper
In his red right hand ♪
[phone ringing]
[phone continues ringing]
[groans]
[breathing heavily]
Yeah?
Wait. Wait, wait, say that again.
No.
No, that cannot be possible!
[machine clicking]
[breathing heavily]
[gasping]
[moaning]
Peter, my beautiful pilot.
Now, will you please fly me
and my winnings back to England?
Ten spoonfuls of sugar for me, please.
Is that for one?
Look, Ruby.
Daddy's back from his call.
Everything's going to be all right now.
[children shouting]
[tyres screech]
[door bangs open]
[machine clicking]
[Michael] No.
Oh, no, no.
No, no, no.
Oh, no.
[snorts]
[sighs]
[phone rings]
Hello.
Arthur! Arthur, where's Tommy?
Just get to him
and tell him that we've lost the lot.
Stay in. Stay put.
You'll hear from Tommy.
Arthur, what are you talking about?
How is that possible?
[Arthur] It's possible because this
morning in New York City at 6:00 a.m.,
the Wall Street stock exchange crashed.
Like a steam train.
And we were most definitely on board.
[woman speaking Chinese]
[people screaming]
[breathing deeply] Fuck it!
[women speaking Chinese]
All right. Come on, get changed.
-Jesus Christ!
-Bring the car round.
[woman screaming]
Got to get out of here.
Hurry up! Come on!
I'm going!
Change of plan.
We're not going to London anymore.
We're going straight to Birmingham.
-There are other passengers.
-Not anymore.
[baby crying]
[women speaking Chinese]
[lift bell chimes]
If you're going to England,
-I'm coming with you.
-No, no, no.
I love you, you love me. That's the truth.
Gina, wait, come on.
I wanna meet your family.
No, you don't.
[gunshot]
-[gunshot]
-[groans]
Oh, fuck.
[groans]
Now you've heard of us.
-[Finn grunting]
-[Aberama] Come on.
-[breathing heavily]
-Couch. Couch!
Put something down for the blood.
My sister'll fucking kill me.
Be fucking careful.
She spends thousands of pounds
on this shit.
[grunts and groans]
[Aberama] Get me some booze.
[yelps]
[screams and groans]
Just fucking get the thing out of me
and sew me up. Just do it.
Peaky boy, give me your blade.
That's enough.
Don't want you throwing up
on your sister's furniture.
[whimpers]
You know what you're doing?
-[Aberama] I've done this a dozen times.
-[Finn breathing heavily]
I once took a bullet from between
two ribs, one inch from the heart.
Mind you, it was a horse. [chuckles]
And the horse did die.
-[both chuckle]
-Hold him. Hold him.
[Finn screams]
[groaning and screaming]
[gasping]
-Here you go.
-[chuckles]
Just a little one.
-[Ada] What the fuck is going on?
-Oh, fuck.
Hello, Ada.
-Get out. Both of you.
-[Finn] Oh, fuck.
Push this on the wound.
Keep up the pressure.
Get out.
I'm so sorry, Ada.
They broke a statue of some thin woman.
Fucking statues.
What has Tommy told you?
Shelbys stay out of the sporting stuff.
What? To maintain your fucking reputation?
Oi!
You listen to me.
We've got a chance.
Tommy has given us that chance.
He's got power, we've got money,
and our past is left behind us.
And you've got a precious young life,
Finn, you fucking idiot!
Three inches to the left
and that would've been gone.
[groans]
You've got nothing to prove, Finn.
You have got nothing to prove.
[Ruby] Daddy! Daddy!
Come here, you.
Come here, come here, come here. Ooh!
Now, what have you been up to, eh?
Any time, Johnny.
All right, you heard the man. Let's go.
Where's Charles?
He's in the wagon. He won't come out.
He heard Johnny talking Rokka.
He understands more Gypsy than we think.
He heard him say you shot the horse.
I told him it was mercy.
I said it's what you do
when a horse gets sick.
He doesn't understand.
Dad, why did you shoot him?
[Tommy] Charlie, get out here now.
Let's get it done.
Charles, come here.
Sit down.
Now listen to me.
Your horse was sick. He was in pain.
The vet couldn't do anything.
Even Curly couldn't do anything.
I put him to sleep.
It's what you do.
-No, it's what you do!
-[Tommy] Charlie.
[Charlie] Shoot horses, shoot people.
Everybody says!
[door opens]
[door closes]
[sighs]
[lighter clicking]
[coughing]
Come here.
Dangerous, my beautiful horse.
Too wild to race.
Wouldn't take the reins or the whip.
Should have been a war horse.
Got tired of the pasture.
Couldn't stick the peace and the quiet,
gave up on life...
And he's now free.
In the bleak...
You're crying?
[Dangerous snorts]
[Dangerous neighs]
Tom, I'm sorry.
I didn't know your boy spoke Rokka.
-[car approaching]
-[horn honking]
Fill it in, Johnny.
Take her.
I've called the house. The office.
But if I tell you, you won't believe it.
So I'll show you.
Huh?
I told Michael on Friday
this was going to happen.
[Arthur] Yeah.
Fucking Michael said he was advised by
the broker that the prices would rebound.
Everybody was told the same thing.
He held on.
-Michael held on...
-Yeah.
Michael.
[Tommy] Michael held on.
[Arthur] Yeah.
Michael held on,
and carried on dancing and playing
and fucking in the snow.
Charlie!
Charlie, come out here now.
The kid never fucking listens.
He never listens, Lizzie.
[screaming] What do I have to do
to make people fucking listen to me?
Holy fuck.
[Arthur] What do we do now, Tommy, eh?
What do we do?
Lizzie, you go with Arthur to Birmingham.
You stay in the Midland Hotel.
[snaps fingers]
Arthur, call a full meeting for
the board of directors tomorrow at noon.
A full fucking meeting.
What about today, eh?
What's wrong with today, Tom?
[Tommy] Need to do some thinking.
Oh. Oh, you do that best
on your own, don't you, eh?
I won't be on my own. I'm never on my own.
Lizzie, you have the driver
come back tomorrow.
And Arthur, tell my boy that sometimes,
death is a kindness.
Come on.
[horse whinnies]
[Tommy] What now?
[Grace] What am I, a genie?
You summon me up
with your little bottle of dope.
I take it for the pain and to keep warm.
Is that what it's for?
The warmth?
[sighs]
[whispers] The warmth.
All this time...
[Grace] I know.
Our love still remains.
But you have to listen
to the voices that you hear.
Do what they tell you to do.
Too much to do, Grace.
The kids...
No need to say goodbye.
[horse snorting]
No need to sleep.
Just think, Tom.
[snorts]
-[Arthur] Linda!
-[footsteps approaching]
[whispers] Fuck.
[door opens]
Oh.
[door closes]
There you are, eh?
[door locks]
[Linda] You're the chairman, Arthur,
so start acting like one.
Chairman, am I? Hmm?
No.
I'm the fucking doorman, Linda.
Hmm?
And you ain't coming in here tonight,
love, dressed like that.
Tommy made me the chairman
so that he could stay clean.
It's called an arrangement.
It's an opportunity.
I know who I am, Linda.
I know who I am,
and I'm all right with it.
Finally. Hmm.
I can live with it.
I need you to be all right with it.
Eh?
What is it, eh?
And what do you want, hmm?
Would you want the chairman, do you?
With his fancy briefcase?
And his gold fountain pen, eh?
Hmm? [chuckles]
What do you want?
Chairman or doorman, hmm?
You think we can fuck and it'll be okay,
and I'll be quiet? Well, I won't.
Every week, your brother's down in London
making out he's fucking Robin Hood,
champion of the people,
while you're up here
running the racket for him.
And according to your arrangement,
if anything should happen,
it'd be you who takes the blame,
does the time, or swings for it.
And what do you want?
I want you...
[Arthur inhales sharply]
...to take the opportunity
that God and the New York Stock Exchange
-has presented to you.
-[footsteps approaching]
[knocking at door]
[Edna] Mr Shelby, the meeting
will be starting soon.
Yeah, all right.
Be right there.
[Arthur] Thank you, Edna.
And shut the door!
[door closes]
[Linda clears throat]
Okay, now.
Hmm. Very nice.
Let's begin.
Yesterday, as you all know,
there was a fucking terrible...
There was a terrible disaster.
Hmm?
It wasn't just for us,
it was for the whole world.
It happened in New York.
That's where it happened.
And it slowly spread to London.
And then to, er, fucking Hong Kong. Hmm?
The whole thing...
The whole thing went up.
Well, actually, the whole thing
went fucking down, but...
[Arthur clears throat]
We wasn't the only ones hurt by this.
Whole world is hurt, a lot of people.
In the papers.
It's all over the news.
Everyone's talking about it.
Arthur,
shouldn't we just wait for Thomas?
[chuckles] Polly, Arthur's now
the chairman of the board.
[Greene] Er, Mr Chairman,
perhaps while we wait for Thomas,
I might lighten the gloom and express,
as a relatively new member
of this company,
what a pleasure it is to be in a boardroom
that has so many females in it.
Yeah, and all are females who are
both... sharp-witted and decorative.
[Arthur] Yeah, well,
we're a very modern company, Mr Greene.
Indeed.
Although, there are still some amongst us
who cling to their old-fashioned values.
[door opens]
How far have we got?
We've established
that ladies are decorative.
[Arthur] We've only just sat down, Tom.
Actually, erm, Arthur has some documents
that he'd like to hand out.
[Tommy] Yeah?
What documents?
I was just explaining
to everyone, Tom, that, erm...
well, we're fucked. Ain't that right, hmm?
Yes and no. [clears throat]
It is true that a large proportion
of the company's funds
were invested in American stocks
and shares.
Invested or hidden?
All investments are approved
by the board, Linda.
Only the ones that went
through the books, Thomas.
Linda, after this meeting, there will be
another meeting, for just family.
Did we vote on this?
Arthur--
[mocking] "Arthur,
can't you control your wife?"
We are a very modern company, Mr Greene.
[Tommy clears throat]
To be precise, everything we channelled
through the New York Stock Exchange
is now offering a return
of ten cents to the dollar.
[scoffs]
And the Nolan Bank of America,
where we invested our fluidity,
is offering five cents to the dollar
on all deposits.
Yeah.
[sighs]
But there is hope.
Why? What have you got in there,
a magic wand?
As non-executive director of the company,
I need permission from the chairman
to present my strategy to the board.
Permission granted, Tom.
[scoffs]
♪ Misty morning, clouds in the sky ♪
♪ Without warning, a wizard walks by ♪
♪ Casting his shadow, weaving his spell ♪
♪ Funny clothes, twinkling bell ♪
♪ Never talking
Just keeps walking ♪
♪ Causing his magic ♪
The Peaky Blinders are coming.
Micky, the Peaky Blinders are coming.
[Micky] Ladies and gents. Peaky Blinders
are on the way. Please vacate. Thank you.
[indistinct chatter]
[customers cheering and clapping]
-[Tommy] Good to see you.
-[man 1] Mr Shelby.
-[man 2] Mr Shelby.
-Yeah.
Thank you for what you did.
What did I do?
He was gonna evict us,
that bastard, Fellows.
Now he's cut our rent in half. [chuckles]
Good. Glad to hear it. Glad to hear it.
[Arthur] That was a strong lesson for him.
How far can we go, Mr Shelby,
with this beautiful dream?
All the way, brother. All the way.
-Revolution, man.
-[crowd] Yeah.
This crash, Mr Shelby, they're saying
they're gonna cut my hours.
-Yeah? Where do you work?
-Greenhams Engineering.
Greenham Brothers, I know them.
They're not gonna cut your hours.
God bless you. God bless you both.
[Arthur] Enjoy your drink.
[Tommy] Gentlemen and ladies,
if you could all move into the Saloon bar,
where you will all be served
a free pint of Stingo.
[crowd cheers]
[Tommy] Any man who served in France
gets a brandy chaser.
Yeah!
[Tommy] Despite what you're reading
in the newspapers,
I want to hear singing and laughing.
Fuck the stock market!
[crowd] Fuck the stock market!
They backed the wrong horses.
So fucking what, eh?
Thank you, Mr Shelby.
A politician who gets things done.
[Tommy] You're welcome. You're welcome.
[Ada] Get down off the furniture.
[Arthur] Sorry, Ada.
I get excited, don't I?
[door closes]
Right...
Can I begin this family meeting
with a proposal?
From now on,
we find somewhere else to meet?
Your husband believes that being seen
mixing with the common people
is good politics.
Hmm. Well, if this is our campaign
for socialism,
perhaps next time, Polly, you won't wear
earrings worth more than the pub.
Right. Family meeting. First item.
[Ada] This.
Dug out of our Finn's arm yesterday
by Aberama Gold
using your gin and a razor blade.
Finn?
He says they were sent
to Limehouse. Chinatown.
Sent by fucking who?
Sent by me. [clears throat]
I told Finn to stay out of it.
He obviously didn't listen.
[scoffs]
Oh, Tommy, sweetheart, I listen to you.
I listen to you when you tell me
no more sport for anyone named Shelby.
I listen to you when you make me promises.
What's in Chinatown, Tommy?
What the fuck is going on?
[sighs]
Fifty thousand pound. In cash.
He said they were sent
to Chinatown to kill somebody.
[groans]
That kid needs educating,
Tommy, he really does.
Jesus Christ, Tommy!
It was a particular opportunity.
A particular opportunity
presented to me in confidence.
I dealt with it in confidence.
But you told Polly.
Tommy told me that there was a pimp
in East London who sold kids.
Fucking kids, Lizzie, eh? Hmm?
This pimp was blackmailing a senior member
of the House of Lords. A very wealthy man.
Now this pimp is lying in a ditch.
Covered in flies.
World's a better place.
Holy fuck. So now your business
is improving the world.
[Arthur] Sometimes, Ada...
killing is a kindness.
Hmm?
The man we did the job for
is a High Court judge.
We received intelligence from
a senior police officer at Scotland Yard.
I've made lots of new friends in London.
Men with influence.
The police felt the same way
about this pimp as we did.
He wasn't worth a trial.
The coppers cleared the streets for us.
This work was commissioned
by a High Court judge,
by Scotland Yard
and by the House of Lords.
It's a particular opportunity.
It's not to be repeated.
-And it was the right thing to do.
-Fucking right.
Lizzie, you need to understand.
That you tell Polly, not me.
You need to understand
that the corridors of Westminster
are very dimly lit,
and for those who make the rules,
there are no rules.
We own the ropes.
Who's gonna hang us now, eh?
-"We"? We own the ropes, do we?
-Lizzie?
Lizzie, if Finn had listened to me,
you wouldn't have known.
When we go home, I'll explain.
[scoffs]
[Lizzie] I can't be bothered
with this shit.
[door opens]
-So. Tommy Shelby, MP.
-[door closes]
Business as usual.
The strategy I outlined earlier
to rebuild the conventional part
of this business will take time.
In the meantime--
Just business as fucking usual!
In the meantime,
it is fortunate that we have maintained
other sources of cash income.
Because until the stock market recovers,
cash is king.
And cash we have.
No one is gonna hang you, Tommy.
You're gonna hang yourself.
Someone has to pay for them paintings
on your wall, Ada.
Yeah, bye-bye, Ada.
[door closes]
You need to go easy on Ada.
[Tommy] Polly.
When am I ever not easy on Ada, eh?
Thomas, the thing is, Ada...
-She's pregnant.
-[coughing]
Ada's what?
These days, people tell me things
without even speaking.
[Arthur] Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Ada's fucking pregnant, hmm?
And Polly, you need to reassure Ada
that it's 1929, times have changed,
we have a lot to do,
and no one gives a fuck who the father is.
Really?
I already know who the father is.
[sighs]
But we've had enough shocks for one day.
Okay.
[door opens]
[door closes]
All right, go on then.
How long you known about Ada, huh?
I know her doctor. He calls me.
Yeah, longer than me.
Have a look at this.
What's that funny writing on there?
Chinese.
Ah. Right.
And what is it, hmm?
Bad news?
Maybe.
[children chattering]
-[Arthur] Angels of Retribution?
-[Tommy] Yeah.
Burn the letter they sent.
It's already done.
Look at that, Tom.
Pulled from our brother, eh?
Finally took a first bullet. [chuckles]
No one fucking listens to me.
Here, give it here. I'll keep it for him.
-I still have my first one.
-[chuckling] Yeah.
[crowd singing in distance]
Arthur, you can tell our comrades
they can come back in.
Where you going, brother?
♪ I really wanna fight for my country
Just like the old boys and Nazis ♪
♪ Gotta feel it, know who's the enemy
Execution and familiarity ♪
♪ Man is seeking, damn he's gotta destroy
Comprehend the race war, it's in ploy ♪
♪ Gotta keep that dopamine joy ♪
♪ Man, I gotta feel alive now ♪
[man] The huge losses
on the British stock exchange
will bite into our economy
for the foreseeable future.
I therefore must ask the trade unions
to possess understanding.
The need for their
flexibility and cooperation
is paramount in the coming months
as we attempt to rebuild
this great nation.
[indistinct murmuring]
[speaker] Mr Thomas Shelby.
Thank you, Mr Speaker.
My Right Honourable Friend,
the member for Epping,
asks that following the crash,
trade union members be more flexible
when carrying out their duties.
What he's really asking is that
the working man carry the can.
[murmuring]
The grand casino in Monte Carlo
is a small and timid affair
when compared to the wild games of chance
being played in London and New York
by gamblers in silk gloves
and beaver hats,
and when they lose their bets,
turn around and ask
the shoe-shine to pay for it.
[crowd laughing]
Well, on behalf of the shoe-shines
and the can-carriers of South Birmingham
and all across Great Britain,
I would suggest that those
who so recklessly lost their fortunes
on the capitalist lottery
-learn to shine their own shoes...
-[crowd] Yes.
-...carry their own cans...
-Yes.
...and pay their own bills.
-[crowd cheering and clapping]
-Yeah!
[man] Er, Mr Shelby?
I just wanted to say
how much I enjoyed your speech.
You speak very eloquently.
Thank you.
My name's Mosley, by the way,
Oswald Mosley.
Yeah, I know who you are.
My constituency borders yours.
And let me just say,
you've come to my attention.
[knocking at door]
Come.
[door opens]
[Suckerby] Ah.
I have bad news, Mister...
Shelby.
We agreed £50,000
on completion of business.
My wife and I have had a misfortune
on the London Exchange.
There's £20,000 there.
You'll have to wait for the rest.
[sighs]
Cavalry, eh?
-Mmm.
-[chuckles]
Yeah.
I spent a long time
waiting for the cavalry, me.
One time, me and my comrades
waited three days.
When the cavalry finally came,
an officer on the back
of a fine white horse
joked that he'd been delayed
playing a game of whist.
So, I took out my Webley revolver
and I shot him in the head,
stole his horse,
reported him for cowardice.
All for a game of chance.
After my people completed their task
in Chinatown,
they collected all the photographs,
letters and cheques
that were causing you concern.
I now have them in a safe place.
On Monday, you will give me
the full £50,000 in cash,
or I will steal your white horse
from under you.
How the fuck did a man like you
get into a position of trust
in a place of power and privilege?
A man like me?
Lord Suckerby,
I've seen the photographs.
Monday.
[door opens]
-Shelby!
-[door closes]
[Younger] Sorry I'm late, Ada.
We've been having briefings
from the Home Office.
The police are concerned about the effect
of the crash in industrial areas.
-[Ada] Ah.
-Everything all right?
[sighing] Yeah, fine.
We lost money in New York,
so I've been up late.
Has your brother been busy?
Er, he's had two meetings
with Mr Shapurji Saklatvala,
former communist MP of Battersea.
He's been approached
by an anarchist group in Walsall,
he's setting up a meeting.
And there's talk of a mass walkout
of bus drivers,
Nottingham and Derby,
organised by two communist conveners,
not formally known to Special Branch.
He's also had a telephone conversation
with Jessie Eden,
who is organising a committee
to resist wage cuts across the city,
but he'll report more when he sees her.
It's all in there, though.
Names and everything.
I heard he had the Labour benches
roaring approval in the House today.
Hmm.
If only he meant it, he'd be dangerous.
I didn't know you drank stout, Ada.
I thought it was gin.
Times are hard.
Hmm.
Exactly how much did you lose?
[sighs] Don't worry about it.
Tommy has a plan.
He thinks that we can turn the collapse
of the stock exchange to our advantage.
He says, "When others retreat,
you advance."
He says we can wave cash
in the faces of desperate men.
You tell your brother from me,
he's doing excellent work.
I'm told two more military contracts for
vehicles and parts for the army in India
-are on their way to him.
-Yeah.
[Ada chuckles softly]
Er...
[exhales heavily]
Fuck!
[sighs]
[knocking]
[Tommy] Come.
Mr Shelby, this arrived from New York.
It's from Winston Churchill.
He says he was in New York
and had dinner with Charlie Chaplin,
and Chaplin mentioned your name.
So, he's in New York,
and he doesn't mention the crash.
No. Even though, in the bar last night,
Mr Churchill's private secretary reckoned
he lost £75,000 in two hours.
And you?
Were you affected, Mr Shelby?
I'm going to my apartment, Adam.
You lock up.
Sorry, Mr Shelby,
you have one more appointment.
You set it yourself.
It's in the diary from last week.
A journalist from the Times.
He used to be with the Birmingham Mail.
He sent you some questions.
You said you wanted to meet him.
He's outside.
Yes.
Send him in.
[sighs]
Er, Mr Shelby?
Mr Levitt from the London Times.
Have a seat.
Adam, you go home. I'll lock up.
Mr Shelby, do you remember me?
No.
Once, in Small Heath, you were
burning photographs of the king.
London Times. You've done well.
As have you, sir.
To put it mildly.
I sent you a list of questions.
Yeah, I misplaced them.
-Yeah, well, you have a lot on your plate.
-Yes.
All I remember is that
your questions interested me.
Oh.
Good.
Sorry, this...
Ah. Here we are.
Yes, erm...
[clears throat]
Shall we, erm...
So, Mr Shelby,
traditionally in this country,
print journalists
take no interest in the, er...
in the private lives of politicians.
"Private lives"?
But in these modern times,
especially in America,
journalists are beginning to...
[stammering]
Well, that is to say, yes, erm, shall I...
So, readers are beginning to say...
Want to know more about
the men who represent them.
Of course.
In these modern times.
Whereas, before, it would have been
seen as ungentlemanly
to ask a public figure questions about
personal matters or business affairs--
Oh, well, no need to worry.
I'm no gentleman.
Hmm.
Er, Mr Shelby, as I said in my letter,
ten years ago, I was a journalist
on the Birmingham Evening Mail.
And, of course, working in that city,
it was impossible not to know your name.
And your reputation.
[sighs]
So, when I saw that you had been elected
as a Socialist--
You reflected on the fact
that working people
can indeed change their lives
for the better.
Channel their abilities in new directions.
Discover better methods.
Aim for happier outcomes.
Even win awards for industry.
You can write this down, Mr Levitt.
The question I have for you,
Mr Shelby, is this.
Was your conversion from bookmaker
to socialist politician
a gradual thing, or...
-a road to Damascus experience?
-[chuckles]
Yeah.
Now I hear that question.
I remember receiving your letters,
and I distinctly remember
your use of the word "bookmaker".
Er... You...
Were you not a bookmaker, sir?
Yes. I gained a licence in 1919
for on-track betting.
But since 1923, I've made my fortune
in the manufacture,
sale and export of motorcars.
And lately, gin.
And lately, three new homes
for orphaned children.
You can write all this down, Mr Levitt.
I have another question, Mr Shelby.
In Birmingham,
at the time that I was there...
there was a Major Campbell.
He was found dead.
A member of your family was charged.
[chuckles]
[sighs]
All right, you answer me this.
Answer me this.
What is your Tory newspaper
more afraid of?
Is it evolution or revolution?
And what is it about
working-class men like me,
standing up in the House of Commons
and speaking from the heart?
What is it that so troubles you
that you would try to undermine me?
I am talking about specific events, sir.
Which I don't recall.
With which I was never personally linked.
And after which,
all convictions were quashed.
Yeah, now I... [smacks lips]
I recall receiving your letter.
And I recall that when I did,
I asked a colleague of mine
to carry out some research.
Just a moment.
Here we are.
Ah.
Michael Levitt, correct?
-Yes.
Journalist.
Unmarried.
Apartment in Maida Vale.
An apartment opposite
the Underground station.
"Unmarried" is underlined.
"Mr Levitt enjoys walks in the park.
Sometimes alone.
Sometimes not alone.
Sometimes with other men."
[exhales heavily]
"Sometimes with other men."
I'm old-fashioned, Michael.
I believe private lives
should remain private.
Not everything modern is good, now, is it?
You gonna write this down...
in your little fucking book?
[door opens]
[Polly] Well?
Not yet. I didn't tell him.
Him knowing or not knowing
has no relevance to what we are drinking.
[Ada chuckles softly]
It's vintage.
-Fuck it.
-[chuckles]
This... is for us.
Let's drink to the baby.
Polly, do you remember
when I was last pregnant?
You were gonna take me to Cardiff.
I was gonna get rid of it.
What about this time?
Imagine.
The father's scared.
He runs away.
You're left.
[Ada sighs]
Oh, sweetheart.
The baby's black, he's a bastard,
and it's Birmingham.
But you don't care...
because the world has changed.
And the baby's eyes are golden.
And you're gonna leave her with Aunt Polly
every day to look after.
Aunt Polly who insisted
that you called her Elizabeth.
How do you know it's a "her"?
'Cause I'm Polly Gray.
It's a girl?
Golden.
[chuckles]
To be born in the year 1930,
where everything will be changed
for the better.
She'll be the colour of a Hollywood Oscar.
[chuckles softly]
What will Tommy say?
Tommy knows.
[chuckles]
Hmm.
He's also seen that the world's big
and round, and he says, "So what?"
Tommy is right, you know, Ada.
We are flying above the rules now.
[chuckles]
We're bold people, aren't we, Polly?
That's the beauty.
Hello, Cyril.
At least you're still talking to me.
Where is everyone?
Your wife is upstairs with Ruby.
You know, Frances,
if there were to be a snap election
in this house today,
wouldn't win it.
Even if I were running
against the devil himself.
Oh.
-I gathered.
-Hmm.
Where's Charles?
Charles is in the stable.
Thank you.
[Tommy clears throat]
Did Arthur explain?
He said it's God's will.
But you're not God!
[sighs] No, I'm not God.
Not yet.
[footsteps approaching]
[theme song playing]
♪ On a gathering storm comes
A tall handsome man ♪
♪ In a dusty black coat
With a red right hand ♪
♪ A shadow is cast wherever he stands ♪
♪ Stacks of green paper
In his red right hand ♪